Hello friends welcome to your own channel Daily
Stock in today's video I am going to
tell you the analysis of ICICI Lord company
and will also tell you whether you should invest in this company
or should put it in
your watch list for short term investment so
I am going to
give you all this information in this video so you
must watch this video till the end this
is a very important video and friends if you like
my video then please subscribe to my channel
because if
you do not like my content then you
can unsubscribe till the end
because if you like my channel, if you like
my content then only you should
subscribe to my channel because
this will let me know whether I have really
some good content or
not so now I am starting the video so
see first of all we will know
what does ICICI Lord General Insurance Company work see there are two types of
insurance one is life insurance
one is general insurance
okay life insurance means a policy related to a person's life
means if you live for so many years then
after that you will get this much maturity also this is how it is
general
Insurance means if you are getting your car, your
bungalow, your shop insured, then
all those things
come under general insurance, so
ICICI Lombard only
makes general insurance, which means there are
no life insurance policies here, there are general
insurance policies and it is
a private sector company, which means it is
not a government company, II Bank has its
own company, so see, yesterday I
told you the analysis of ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company, so it is
only life insurance, which means there are only life insurance policies there, so it is
a different life insurance
company and this company is a general insurance company, which
means if you also want to get
your bungalow or your car
insured, then you
can do it through ICICI Lombard, so
you understand that ICICI
Lombard is a general insurance company and
ICICI Prudential Life Insurance Company
insures life insurance, so see, its
work is absolutely good and the main thing is that it is an
insurance business and the
insurance business  So I
personally feel that this business can never stop. There is
a reason behind this.
Tell me one thing, have you insured your house today? Have
you insured all the vehicles in your house
or not? So
tell me yourself whether this company can be closed. Whatever is being
used in every house is being
insured. This
means that there will be at least 1015 insurances in every house, including
general insurance, car, bungalow, everything.
So this is one thing. This business can never stop
because every person
needs his security. So it is a simple
thing that this business can never stop.
But in this also we will have to see
which company is good
for investment. So let us now move forward and
look at the fundamentals of the company
and see whether it is
good for investment or
not. So first of all, look at its market cap.
Its market cap is Rs 6743 crore. So
see how high its market cap is.
Its market cap indicates that its
business is high.  And the company's business is
doing quite well, as
indicated by its market cap. However, if
you look at its PV ratio, it's not there,
and its PV ratio is also missing. This
means that some of the company's data is
invalid. However, we'll include other factors as well.
If you look at the company's dividend yield,
it's 0.24 pence. The
company's dividend yield is 0.24 pence. This
means that at the market price, you're only
getting a dividend of 0.24 pence. So,
as a dividend deal, you should
n't invest in this stock. Its dividend is quite
low. If you're
looking for a stock based on dividends, III
Lombard isn't one of them.
Now, if you look at its P ratio
and its PB ratio, they're not visible right now, so that's why I ca
n't tell you. However,
if I calculate its actual
valuation, I'll let you know when I do it.
Now, you can see the company's financials.
If you look at the trend, you will see that
from 2017 to 2020, there is a continuous
growth in the company's revenue and this is a
very good thing. You see, there is
growth in the company's revenue every year, which means the
sales of the company, that is, the general
insurance that the company is selling, is
showing better performance every year. The
sales of the company are increasing on a year-on-year basis. This is
visible here by looking at the top line of the company for the last 4 years. So, you see how
well the company is performing. Now, if you look at the
profitability of the company for the last 4 years,
you will see that there was an increase from 2017 to 18,
then there was an increase from 18 to 19
and
you have also seen an increase in the profitability of the company from 19 to 20. So,
you see, the
company is performing very well. The
chart of the company for the last four years, which is the
bottom line and top line of the company, is exactly the same.  It
looks top class and there is
no doubt in it, so this is a very
good thing, if you are its investor then
this is a very good thing for you.
Now if we look at the share holding pattern of the company, then
you will see that the promoter
holding in it is 51.8%. By the way, my
parameter is if the promoter holding is at 50,
then it is a very good thing and it shows
that the promoters of the company have confidence in their company.
Now if I talk about mutual funds, then
mutual funds also have a holding of 10.5%, other
DIIs have a holding of 1% in it and
if we talk about FIIs, then FIIs have
a huge holding in it, you see
27.09.19, this is a very good thing, if
FIIs have invested in it, then
they know that its business is very
good and it can give them a good return.
II Lombard, if I
talk about retail, then the retail holding in it is
equal to 9%, only 8.94%
holding is of retail investors
in it, so you see the main holding  If we
look at it, it is only with the promoters and FIIs. The
remaining small amount of holding is
also with mutual funds. So, the
shareholding pattern of the company
looks quite good.
Now, if you look at the shareholding pattern of the company,
that is, the shareholding pattern of the promoters of the company, there
is definitely a little problem in it because if you look at the shareholding pattern of the
company, the promoters' holding has fallen to 4 in the last one year and three months. That
means, let's
assume roughly 4. The promoter's
holding falling below 4 seems a little problematic,
but one thing is that
they have not sold anything else in the June to September quarter.
Now, if the promoter
holding is at 50, it is a
good thing, but if it
falls further from 50, then I think it is
definitely a matter of some concern. Now, look at the
strengths of the company, all the strengths of the company are
in the green, none are in the red. This is a
very good thing. See, the
holding of mutual funds has increased in this. The
number of mutual funds has increased. FPIs and
FIIs have
increased their investment in this and you  The
holding of institutional investors has also increased, so this is a very
good thing, meaning all the
big holders from outside have made
good investors in it. If you
are its shareholder, then you should remain invested in it,
looking at the holding pattern of its promoters, you should not sell your shares in it.
Now if
I talk about the revenue statement of the company, then it is
given quarter wise, see
from March 2020 to September 2020, now
see this, one quarter from here, second quarter,
now see this, the total income of the company is Rs 593 crore, that is, the
revenue of the company was this much
in March 2020, then after that if
you see, there has been a decline of about Rs 35 crore,
but Rs 35 crore is
not such a huge decline, there is a
decline equal to Rs 10, if we
talk percentage wise, then it
is a decline of only Rs 8, but after that again a
decline of about Rs 17 crore has been seen,
but right now during the Corona period, if the
company still has a decline of about Rs 550 crore  Revenue is coming in,
so I think it's a very
good thing. Now, if I look at the company's
profit at the end of
2020, the company's net profit was Rs 281 crore. Now,
due to the Corona period, the company's expenses are
also decreasing significantly, as you
can see that the company has made a
net profit of Rs 398 crore, while the company's sales have
fallen. Here you
can see the profitability of the company is Rs
117 crore, this is a very
good thing. And after this, you
see here that the company's revenue has fallen by Rs 17 crore,
while the company's profit has
increased by Rs 17 crore, this is a very good thing.
At the end, the bottom line matters to us,
but it is also very important to matter about sales.
But sales are still doing well.
Only a slight decline has been seen in sales. So, the
position of the company is
very good right now.
Now, if I look at the company's earnings,
if I talk about the share,  You see, for the
last 3 years, there has been a continuous growth in the company's earnings
per share. For the
last 3 years, the company's earnings
per share has been increasing continuously. Now look at this, it has increased from 19.23% to
approximately 26.2%. So, the company's
earnings per share looks very good here.
Now if you look at the company's
earnings per share is 26.2% and the current
market price of the company's shares is
around 1500.
So you can imagine from this that it means it comes out to be around a
PE of 5560. Now
after this, if you look at the book value of the company,
you should also look at the company's book value. It has been
increasing continuously for the last 3 years from
104 to
12455 paise, after that it reached
125.7 paise. So, every year, there is growth in the company's book
value. There is
growth in the company's earnings per share.
But if you are its
shareholder, then you might have felt a little sad this time.
Because the company
gave less dividend as compared to last year,
last year the company had given a dividend of ₹
and this time the company has given a dividend of only ₹,
so if .  The dividend has fallen, which
means it is mostly 100%, meaning the dividend of about 90% has
decreased.
Now, if I talk about the company's gross profit
margin percentage, it is
increasing and sometimes decreasing every year. Now,
see, from 2018 to 2019, an increase of about 4% was
seen, then from there again a
decline of 10% was seen, but a
gross profit margin percentage of 86% is
quite good, there is no problem in it.
Now, if I look at the company's
operating margin percentage, the
company's operating margin
percentage is the same, there is no problem in it.
But at the end, if I
look at the company's net profit margin percentage, you will see it, from 64 to 62,
then from there again to 59, which means there is a
slight decline every year, but
59 is a very good percentage and
if the company's profit margin
percentage is this much, then it is very good.
Now let's see what this means. It means
that if the company is selling insurance worth ₹1, then at the end of the year, the
company is making a net profit of 9.43 on it.
Now, look at the company's return on
equity percentage. What you saw last time was
that the company's net profit
margin percentage is declining,
but the company's return on equity is
absolutely excellent, top class. Look,
my parameter is 20, and last year it was
less than that, but this time it has reached 20.9.
This means that the company is
earning a good profit on its capital,
meaning the company is earning a good return on the money of the company's owners.
If I talk about the company's RO, then
you should see that the company's RO is also increasing every year.
Look, a
growth of 5% and then again an increase of 2% has been
seen in the company's RO percentage. Now,
if I talk about the company's return on asset percentage, then
you should see that the
company's return on asset percentage has increased continuously for the last three years.
You've also seen an increase,
and this is a very, very good thing.
It shows that even though the company's profits aren't
that large, the company has generated
a good return on its equity, capital, and assets,
and they've made money for people. The
company's position is currently
excellent, and there's no doubt about that.
But now, when it comes to the company's
liquidity position, look at the company's liquidity position. The company's
liquidity position is very poor, and it appears to be a
very problematic one. The
company's current ratio has been declining continuously for the last three years.
You can see from
0.51 to 0.38, or
0.32. If the company's current ratio
is less than one, it means the company has a cash
inflow problem. Cash flow is
n't coming in well, and
this could cause problems for most companies. The
company may not be able to pay its current liabilities, i.e.,
those debts that the company has to pay within one year. So, the
company's liquidity
position is poor. This is a slight
negative for the company, and the company should focus on this.  This
should be done and if the company's quick ratio is
also seen to be the same, so if the
company's liquidity position at the end
is a little poor, then the company should pay some
attention to this and gradually the
company should focus on its cash inflows.
Now if I talk about the company's debt to equity
ratio, then the company's debt
to equity is exactly equal to 0.
Meaning, in a way, you can also understand
that the company is almost debt free. Now
see, it has gone from 0.10 to 0.09 and in a
way, you can understand that the company is debt free.
One means the company's debt is equal to 0. So, there is
debt but it is equal to 0.
This is a very good thing. Otherwise, if the
company's debt was less than one, then
it would have been considered very good and here the
company's debt is only 0.09. So, in my
opinion, this is a very good thing
because the company does not have to make much interest
payment, hence,
after the revenue the company gets, the company has
more profit in its pocket. Now, if
I look at the company's interest  If I talk about coverage ratio, that is, the
company's ability to pay interest on its debt is also
increasing every year. You can see this, from
30 to 40, from 40 to 43, which means that the company's
ability to pay interest is also
increasing every year, and this is a
very good thing for the company.
Now,
if I talk about ICICI Lord General Insurance Company,
now it is at an all-time
high of 1529, whereas ICICI Lobha
closed at 1485 at the previous closing and
it also showed a rise of about 2% in the previous closing.
See, if I talk about its all-time high, then
you are getting it at a discount of about ₹ from the all-time high
and if I
talk percentage wise, then
you are getting it at a discount of only 3% at the all-time high.
Look at ICICI Lord
and